{
    "id": "340e7b74d2234b96be89e9004491e3b3",
    "title": "Parts Of Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "This wood will make a good hiding place. Here hiding is a/an …………………….",
            "description": "Adjectives are words used to modify nouns. Here the adjective hiding modifies the noun place.",
            "answers": [
                "verb",
                "adverb",
                "adjective"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She was made to repeat the whole story. Here story is a/an …………………….",
            "description": "A noun is the name of a person, place or thing.",
            "answers": [
                "verb",
                "pronoun",
                "noun"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "They lived many miles from the town. Which of the following is the preposition?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "they",
                "many",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The government seems to change its mind a great deal. Here seems is a/an …………………………",
            "description": "The verb is a word that explains what the subject is or what it does. ",
            "answers": [
                "verb",
                "adverb",
                "noun",
                "conjunction"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "In the two weeks in the job he made himself thoroughly disliked. Here thoroughly is a/an ………………………",
            "description": "Most words ending in –ly are adverbs. Here the adverb thoroughly modifies the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "adverb",
                "verb"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Can you make me a birthday cake by Monday? Here me is a/an ……………………..",
            "description": "A pronoun is a word used to refer to the speaker, the person spoken to or the person spoken of.",
            "answers": [
                "noun",
                "pronoun",
                "preposition"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Alice and James got married last week. Here last week is a/an ……………………..",
            "description": "Words indicating time are usually adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "adverb",
                "preposition"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "After three very unhappy years, they divorced. Here after is a/an ……………………",
            "description": "A conjunction is a word used to connect two clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Conjunction",
                "Preposition",
                "Verb"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I have been married to you for twenty years and I still don’t understand you. Here twenty is a/an ……………………..",
            "description": "Both ordinal and cardinal numbers are adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "adverb",
                "verb",
                "noun"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I couldn’t think clearly, and I felt hot. Here felt is a/an …………………….",
            "description": "Verbs are action words. ",
            "answers": [
                "noun",
                "conjunction",
                "verb",
                "adverb"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The manager says that we may leave our coats in the bathroom. Here manager is a/an ……………………….",
            "description": "A noun is the name of a person, place or thing. ",
            "answers": [
                "noun",
                "pronoun",
                "adverb"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The rain made the grass wet. Here wet is a/an ………………………",
            "description": "Adjectives are words that describe a quality. ",
            "answers": [
                "adjective",
                "adverb",
                "verb"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}